ABHINAV ARORA

Fullerton, CA, 92831 | 657-217-7312 |

linkedin.com/in/abhinavarora14799|abhinavaroraa14799@gmail.com| E-Portfolio: www.abhinavarora.life

SUMMARY

Abhinav Arora is a Senior Computer Science major student at California State University Fullerton and an Incoming 2022 Spring Front-end Engineering Intern at SolarInsure Inc. in Costa Mesa, California. An Agile Developer with notable experience in Front End Development, Web-Applications Development, Object Oriented Programming, IT System Administration, and Cloud Computing.

EDUCATION

California State University - Fullerton

August 2018 – May 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Current GPA – 3.45)

DEAN'S LIST - Fall 19, Spring 20.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Proficient in JavaScript, Python, C++, PHP, Laravel, SQL, AWS, Vue.Js, ReactJS, .NET, GIT, Java, Object oriented Programming, Agile Development.

EXPERIENCE

Research & Development Assistant | CareerFair.Al Project - CSUF | Division of Psychology | Cal. State Fullerton

September 2021 - Present

- Developed a custom web-portal to embed virtual agent-mentors to assist students with Career Advising 24/7.
- Leveraged the inbuilt React Toolkit to create frontend features, and responsive web-based User Interface.
- Merged, cleansed, and prepared datasets used to train AI Algorithms and Machine Learning Models.

Information Technology Intern | Sensorex | Garden Grove, California

August 2021 - Present

- Wrote custom HTML, PHP, CSS and JavaScript for existing websites and applications.
- Tested, benched, and built tools for benchmarking ML algorithms on the hardware accelerator.
- Handled visual, responsive implementation of features provided by our product team using Node JS, React JS, React Native.

Student Software Developer | University Data Center – Division of IT | California State University Fullerton

March 2021 – September 2021

- Implement interaction between frontend and backend using the JSON object.
- Monitored all network processes to ensure the smooth flow of data across the network.
- Reduced deployment time by developing bash scripts to automate build and deployment on Ubuntu servers.

Associate Software Developer | EZ-Health Track | Foster City, California

August 2020 - December 2020

- Handled form-data (in JSON) via AJAX-PHP application calls.
- Developed UI pages using JSP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript technologies.
- Incorporated applications, graphics, audio, and video clips into client websites.

Research Student Assistant | OAIE- Division of Academic Affairs | California State University Fullerton

June 2019 – August 2020

- Developed custom data models and algorithms to apply to Data sets and Queries.
- Improved and evaluated data collection processes by assessing, streamlining, automating, and extending existing systems.
- Interpreted data, analyzed results using statistical techniques and generated ongoing reports.

Webmaster | EHS - Division of Administration and Finance | California State University Fullerton

May 2019 - August 2019

- Established, and maintained web system and tested servers and operating management systems.
- Updated and created webpages and maintained them up to mark with ATI compliance.
- Secured and developed system access; monitored, established, and tested disaster recovery procedures.

Front End Development Intern | InfoSoft Technologies | New Delhi, India

July 2017 - January 2018

- Designed and implemented web-based tools for data visualization and data labeling.
- Worked closely with backend engineers to seamlessly integrate with frontend systems using the JSON object.

BOARD POSITION

ACM External Vice President

May 2020 - May 2021

- Handled professional outreach tasks to build relationships with companies and planned professional events.
- Organized, managed, and created Project Jams, Interview practice workshops, and career workshops.
- Lead Product Tank Events which focused on networking events with Alumni working in the Product management roles.

CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services (AWS) - Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF-C01)

September 2021 – September 2024

• IBM - Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner.

August 2021 - Present

PERSONAL \ GROUP PROJECTS

Chrome Speak

November 2018 – March 2019

- Collaborated and created an extension on Google Chrome named as Chrome Speak with Amazon Alexa.
- Added voice control feature for disabled support that assisted webpage navigation on Google Chrome.
- Configured the Initial setup, added google chrome as a client, and hyperlinked the numbering in JS.

Google Maps API

December 2018 - January 2019

- Designed a Program (C++) which integrates Google Maps API hosted in Google's Servers.
- Converted a Physical mailing address to its corresponding geolocations using Geocoding API, also added the Reverse feature.
- Developed the Elevation feature which output the sea-level elevation in feet from coordinates using the Elevation API.

Forkify Recipe

July 2021 – August 2021

- Designed a cookbook application (JavaScript) that contains recipes for multiple different foods within categories.
- Implemented the Food2Fork API which allowed the program to search over 100,000 recipes of different cuisines.

AWARDS & ACCOLADES

Gold Medals in Cyber Olympiad 2016 (State) and International Mathematics Olympiad 2017 (Regional).